Guide to the Merton Stoltz Files 1959-1978
Brown University Library
Merton Stoltz Files
Stoltz (Merton) Files
1959-1978
OF-1CA-S2
John Hay Library University Archives and Manuscripts Box A Brown University Providence, RI, 02912 Telephone: Manuscripts: 401-863-3723; University Archives: 401-863-2148 Email: Manuscripts: hay@brown.edu; University Archives: archives@brown.edu
45 linear feet
Stoltz, Merton
The Merton Stoltz Files include office files, correspondence, and committee files dated from 1959 to 1978. It includes materials from various offices, speeches, projects, and committees regarding the comprehensive involvement of a Provost at the University.
Biographical/Historical Note
Merton Philip Stoltz (1913-1989), provost and acting president of Brown University, was born in Glidden, Wisconsin, on March 28, 1913. He graduated from the University of Minnesota in 1934 and earned a master’s degree at Brown in 1936. After earning his Ph.D. at Minnesota in 1941, he returned to Brown as assistant professor of economics. He was named full professor in 1950. He was chairman of the Department of Economics from 1956 to 1964, associate dean of the Graduate School from 1960 to 1964, and dean of the University from 1964 to 1966. As dean he was actively involved in proposals to the Ford Foundation and in the beginnings of the medical education program. One of the first acts of President Heffner on his arrival was to appoint Stoltz provost of the University, a post which had been vacant since June of 1965. In announcing the appointment Heffner said of his choice, “His integrity, his vision, his sensitivity to Brown traditions, and his demonstrated capacity for leadership make him ideally qualified for the position of principal academic office of this great University.” He was three times acting president of Brown, serving in 1969-70 between the presidencies of Heffner and Hornig, in the summer of 1972 while President Hornig recovered from a heart attack, and in 1976 between the presidencies of Hornig and Swearer. He retired in 1978. As an economist Stoltz was chosen to head the Special Providence Committee on Municipal Revenue in 1957 and served on the Rhode Island Fiscal Study Commission in 1961. Tougaloo College awarded him an honorary LL.D. degree in 1977, and at Brown’s Commencement that year he received a standing ovation on the announcement by President Swearer of the establishment of the Merton P. Stoltz Professorship. Brown awarded him an honorary LL.D. degree in 1978. He died on August 7, 1989 in Providence.
Collection information
The papers are arranged into 19 series:
Series 1. Outgoing Correspondence (1965-1977): this series includes a chronological arrangement of mostly professional and collegial correspondence.
Series 2. Files: 1963-1965 (1959-1971): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into four sub-series: general, foundations, committees, and academic departments.
Series 3. Files: 1965-1966 (1960-1967): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into three sub-series: committees, general, and academic departments.
Series 4. Files: 1966-1967 (1965-1968): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into three sub-series: committees, general, and academic departments.
Series 5. Files: 1967-1968 (1964-1968): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into three sub-series: committees, general, and academic departments.
Series 6. Files: 1968-1969 (1967-1969): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into three sub-series: committees, general, and academic departments.
Series 7. Files: 1969-1970 (1969-1970): this series includes numerous files concerning committees at Brown University, including committees on community relations, curricular philosophy, student strikes, and Tougaloo College.
Series 8. Files: 1970-1971 (1970-1971): this series includes numerous files, arranged mostly alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: committees and academic departments.
Series 9. Files: 1971-1972 (1971-1972): this series includes numerous files, arranged mostly alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: committees and academic departments.
Series 10. Files: 1972-1973 (1972-1973): this series includes numerous files, arranged mostly alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: committees and academic departments.
Series 11. Files: 1973-1974 (1973-1974): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: general and academic departments.
Series 12. Files: 1974-1975 (1974-1975): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: general and academic departments.
Series 13. Files: 1975-1976 (1975-1976): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: general and academic departments.
Series 14. Files: 1976-1977 (1976-1977): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: general and academic departments.
Series 15. Files: 1977-1978 (1977-1978): this series includes numerous files, arranged alphabetically, from Stoltz’s responsibilities in the University. The series is divided into two sub-series: general and academic departments.
Series 16. Historical Files (1968-1973): this short series includes documents concerning budget request forms, black student enrollment, and other planning committees.
Series 17. Committees (1973-1978): this series includes files from several discussing policy at Brown, including an academic policy, calendar, library, and promotion committees. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series 18. Internal Committees (1977-1978): this series contains documents concerning administrative committees. Included are documents from investment committees, faculty meetings, audit committees, and documents directly about Merton Stoltz. The series is mostly arranged chronologically.
Series 19. Grants (1964-1977): this series contains documents and files concerning several grant applications and programs. Most documents are applications for grants for the construction of university buildings, including the Sciences Library, Pembroke Dorms, Art Building, and Geo-Math Complex.
There are no restrictions on access, except that the collection can only be seen by prior appointment. Some materials may be stored off-site and cannot be produced on the same day on which they are requested.
This collection is divided into 19 series and further subseries. Most series are arranged either chronologically or alphabetically.
Series 1. Outgoing Correspondence
Series 2. Files: 1963-1965
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Foundations
Subseries C. Committees
Subseries D. Academic Departments
Series 3. Files: 1965-1966
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. General
Subseries C. Academic Departments
Series 4. Files: 1966-1967
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. General
Subseries C. Academics Departments
Series 5. Files: 1967-1968
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. General
Subseries C. Academic Departments
Series 6. Files: 1968-1969
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. General
Subseries C. Academic Departments
Series 7. Files: 1969-1970
Subseries A. Committees
Series 8. File: 1970-1971
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 9. Files: 1971-1972
Subseries A. Committees
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 10. Files: 1972-1973
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 11. Files: 1973-1974
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 12. Files: 1974-1975
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 13. Files: 1975-1976
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 14. Files: 1976-1977
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 15. Files: 1977-1978
Subseries A. General
Subseries B. Academic Departments
Series 16. Historical Files
Series 17. Committees
Series 18. Internal Committees
Series 19. Grants
Names
Brown University
Subjects
Brown University--Faculty; Brown University
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1965-1977; Series 1
  - 1965 Jul - 1966 Feb, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder I.1)
  - 1966 Mar - 1966 Jun (Box 1, Folder I.2)
  - 1966 Jul- 1966 Oct (Box 1, Folder I.3)
  - 1966 Nov - 1967 Feb, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder I.4)
  - 1967 Mar - 1967 Jun (Box 2, Folder I.5)
  - 1967 Jul - 1967 Oct (Box 2, Folder I.6)
  - 1967 Nov - 1968 Feb, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder I.7)
  - 1968 Mar - 1968 Jun (Box 3, Folder I.8)
  - 1968 Jul - 1968 Dec (Box 3, Folder I.9)
  - 1969 Jan - 1969 May (Box 4, Folder I.10)
  - 1969 Jun - 1969 Dec (Box 4, Folder I.11)
  - 1970 Jul - 1970 Dec (Box 4, Folder I.12)
  - 1970 Jul - 1970 Dec (Box 5, Folder I.13)
  - 1971 Jan - 1971 Jun (Box 5, Folder I.14)
  - 1971 Jul - 1971 Dec (Box 5, Folder I.15)
  - 1972 Jan - 1972 Jun (Box 6, Folder I.16)
  - 1972 Jul - 1972 Dec (Box 6, Folder I.17)
  - 1973 Jan - 1973 Jun (Box 6, Folder I.18)
  - 1973 Jul - 1973 Dec (Box 7, Folder I.19)
  - 1974 Jul - 1975 Jun, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder I.20)
  - 1975 Jul - 1976 Jun, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder I.21)
  - 1976 Jul - 1977 Jun, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder I.22)
- Files: 1963-1965, 1959-1971; Series 2
  - General, Series 2. Subseries A
    - American Red Cross, 1962 (Box 8, Folder II.1)
    - Associates Program, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder II.2)
    - ATSM Doctoral Fellowships, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.3)
    - Australian National University, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.4)
    - University Proposals--Far East (Chinese Study), 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder II.5)
    - Foundations -- Possible Grants, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.6)
    - Projections for Ford SPE Proposal, 1964 (Box 8, Folder II.7)
    - Ford Foundation -- Second SPE grant Proposal, 1964 (Box 8, Folder II.8)
    - Fulbright and Smith Mundt Acts, 1962 (Box 8, Folder II.9)
    - Graduate Center, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder II.10)
    - Graduate Council, 1964 (Box 8, Folder II.11)
    - Graduate School, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder II.12)
    - Graduate School -- Alumnae Organization, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.13)
    - Graduate School -- M.A. - Linguistics, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.14)
    - Graduate School -- Placement Service, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.15)
    - Proposed Graduate Programs, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.16)
    - Graduate Training -- Visitation Program, 1963 (Box 8, Folder II.17)
    - Latin America Working Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder II.18)
    - Library -- United Arab Republic, 1962 (Box 8, Folder II.19)
    - Linguistic Program, 1962 (Box 8, Folder II.20)
    - M-Program, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder II.21)
    - Management Consulting, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.22)
    - Master Development Plan, 1962 (Box 9, Folder II.23)
    - Three-year Master's Program, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.24)
    - Five-year Master's Program, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder II.25)
    - Medical Education Program -- Feasibility Committee Studies, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.26)
    - Medical Education Program -- Medical Sciences Council, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.27)
    - Medical Education, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder II.28)
    - Charles E. Merrill Trust, 1960-1964 (Box 9, Folder II.29)
    - National Association of Mutual Savings Banks, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.30)
    - National Institute of Health, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.31)
    - National Science Foundation -- General, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder II.32)
    - NSF Training Grants -- Capacity Data, 1963 (Box 9, Folder II.33)
    - New England Council -- Publication Prize Program, 1962 (Box 9, Folder II.34)
    - New England Economic Research Foundation, 1963 (Box 9, Folder II.35)
    - Peace Corps, 1961 (Box 9, Folder II.36)
    - Pembroke, 1963 (Box 9, Folder II.37)
    - Retirement Plan, 1963 (Box 9, Folder II.38)
    - Proposal for New Science Library, [undated] (Box 9, Folder II.39)
    - Space Sciences Committee, 1963 (Box 9, Folder II.40)
    - Speeches, [undated] (Box 9, Folder II.41)
    - Conference on Hospital Relations, 1965 (Box 9, Folder II.42)
    - Fifteen-Month M.A. Program, 1964 (Box 9, Folder II.43)
    - Population Laboratory, 1965 (Box 9, Folder II.44)
    - Tougaloo, 1963 (Box 10, Folder II.45)
    - Tougaloo, 1964 (Box 10, Folder II.46)
    - Tougaloo, 1965 (Box 10, Folder II.47)
    - Touglaoo Space Utilization Study, [undated] (Box 10, Folder II.48)
    - Foundations, 1964 (Box 10, Folder II.49)
    - The American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder II.50)
  - Foundations, Series 2. Subseries B
    - Samuel S. Fels Fund, 1965 (Box 10, Folder II.51)
    - Ford Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder II.52)
    - Ford Foundation -- Second SPE Grant Proposal -- Draft, 1964 (Box 10, Folder II.53)
    - Ford Foundation -- Three-year Master's Program, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder II.54)
    - Ford Foundation -- Four-year Master's Program, 1965 (Box 10, Folder II.55)
    - Indiana University Foundation, 1964 (Box 10, Folder II.56)
    - Kresge Foundation, 1964 (Box 10, Folder II.57)
    - New England Research Foundation, 1965 (Box 10, Folder II.58)
    - National Science Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder II.59)
    - NSF -- Biology, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder II.60)
    - NSF -- Institute for College Teachers of Science, Math and English, 1964 (Box 11, Folder II.61)
    - Equal Opportunity Act, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.62)
    - Higher Education Facilities -- Act of 1963, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder II.63)
    - NASA Traineeships, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder II.64)
    - NASA Fellowships, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.65)
    - NASA Proposal, 1964 (Box 11, Folder II.66)
    - NDEA Loans, 1964 (Box 11, Folder II.67)
    - NDEA Title IV, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.68)
    - NDEA Title IV -- Institutional, 1960-1971 (Box 11, Folder II.69)
    - Application for Title IV -- NDEA Fellowships, [undated] (Box 11, Folder II.70)
    - NDEA Proposal, 1965 (Box 11, Folder II.71)
    - NDEA Title VI (Chinese), 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.72)
    - NDEA -- Title IV and VI, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.73)
    - Work-Study Program, 1965 (Box 11, Folder II.74)
    - Zenas R. Bliss, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.75)
    - F. Morris Cochran, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.76)
    - Wilbur N. Moulton, 1965 (Box 11, Folder II.77)
    - M.S. Stevens, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.78)
    - Pembroke -- Overseas Educational Fund, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.79)
    - Graduate school, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.80)
    - Peter Magrath, Associate Dean, 1965 (Box 11, Folder II.81)
    - Graduate Housing, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder II.82)
    - South Main, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder II.83)
  - Committees, Series 2. Subseries C
    - Appointment Approvals, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.84)
    - College Research Center, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.85)
    - Faculty -- General, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.86)
    - NEC -- Research Advisory Committee, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.87)
    - Providence Institution for Savings, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.88)
    - Committee on Latin American Programs, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.89)
    - Committee on Organization, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.90)
    - Bio-Medical Center, 1965 (Box 12, Folder II.91)
    - Graduate Center, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.92)
    - Humanities Building, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.93)
    - Shepley Bulfinch (Architects), 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.94)
    - HHFA, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.95)
    - Committee on Second Campus -- Mount Hope, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.96)
    - Committee on Tenure, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.97)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1965 (Box 12, Folder II.98)
    - National Association of Mutual Savings Banks, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.99)
    - Child Health and Development, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.100)
    - Economics and Engineering, 1964 (Box 12, Folder II.101)
    - Far East Language and Area Center, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.102)
    - Title VI Proposal, 1965 (Box 12, Folder II.103)
    - Chinese Collection, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder II.104)
    - Medical Science Program, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.105)
    - Medical Program Correspondence -- Paul Fenton, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.106)
    - Medical Program -- Hospital Relations, 1965 (Box 13, Folder II.107)
    - Personnel, 1965 (Box 13, Folder II.108)
    - Projected Scholarship Needs, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.109)
    - Taxation of Assistants' Stipends and Fellowships, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.110)
  - Academic Departments, Series 2. Subseries D
    - Art, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.111)
    - Botany, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.112)
    - Classics, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.113)
    - Economics, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.114)
    - Engineering, 1964 (Box 13, Folder II.115)
    - French, 1965 (Box 13, Folder II.116)
    - Geology, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.117)
    - German, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.118)
    - Medical Science, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.119)
    - Music, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder II.120)
    - Physics, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.121)
    - Political Science, 1965 (Box 13, Folder II.122)
    - Religious Studies, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder II.123)
- Files: 1965-1966, 1960-1967; Series 3
  - Committees, Series 3. Subseries A
    - ARPA Executive Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.1)
    - Biomedical Science Support Grant Committee for Review, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.2)
    - Committee on Management of Annmary Brown Memorial, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.3)
    - Development Council, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.4)
    - Committee on Environmental Studies, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.5)
    - Research and Investigation Involving Human Beings -- Committee for, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.6)
    - Planning and Building Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.7)
    - Athletic Complex, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.8)
    - Bio-Medical Complex, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.9)
    - Earth Science Building, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.10)
    - Graduate Center, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.11)
    - Pembroke Dormitory Construction, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.11A)
    - Humanities Building, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.12)
    - Physical Sciences Building, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder III.13)
    - Physical Sciences Library -- Grant Application Analysis, 1965 (Box 14, Folder III.14)
    - Committee on Second Campus -- Mount Hope, 1965 (Box 14, Folder III.15)
    - Space Sciences Committee, 1966 (Box 14, Folder III.16)
    - Committee on Structure, 1965 (Box 15, Folder III.17)
    - Committee on Summer Stipends, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.18)
    - EPCO Meeting, 1965 (Box 15, Folder III.19)
    - New England Economic Research Foundation, 1965 (Box 15, Folder III.20)
    - NEC -- Research Advisory Council, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.21)
  - General, Series 3. Subseries B
    - Admissions, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.22)
    - Associates Program, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.23)
    - "B" Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 15, Folder III.24)
    - Chaplains, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder III.25)
    - F. Morris Cochran, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.26)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.27)
    - Dean of the College, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.28)
    - Dean of Pembroke College, 1965 (Box 15, Folder III.29)
    - East Asia Language and Area Center, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.30)
    - Ford Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.31)
    - General Faculty Research Reserve Fund, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.32)
    - Biomedical Sciences Support Grant -- Proposal, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.33)
    - NASA, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.34)
    - NASA Proposal, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.35)
    - NDEA, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.36)
    - NDEA -- fellowships Application and Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder III.37)
    - NDEA Title VI, NDEA Fellowships, 1966 (Box 15, Folder III.38)
    - NDEA Title IV, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder III.39)
    - NSF -- Graduate Traineeships in Engineering, Math and Physical Sciences, 1965 (Box 16, Folder III.40)
    - NSF Institutional Grant #1, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.41)
    - NSF Institutional Grant #2, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.42)
    - NSF -- Senior Foreign Scientist Program, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.43)
    - NSF Undergraduate Instructional Scientific Equipment Program, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.44)
    - SPE Grant -- Ford Foundation Proposal #1, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.45)
    - SPE Grant -- Ford Foundation Proposal #2, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.46)
    - Graduate School (General), 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.47)
    - Dean Lindsay, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.48)
    - C. Peter Magrath, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.49)
    - South Main, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.50)
    - Ray L. Heffner, 1966 (Box 16, Folder III.51)
    - Child Health and Development, 1966 (Box 16, Folder III.52)
    - Institute for Health Services, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder III.53)
    - James Foundation, 1965 (Box 16, Folder III.54)
    - Kress Foundation, 1965 (Box 16, Folder III.55)
    - F. Lennon, 1966 (Box 16, Folder III.56)
    - Arthur D. Little, Inc., 1965-1967 (Box 16, Folder III.57)
    - M-Program, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.58)
    - Middle Eastern Conference, 1966 (Box 17, Folder III.59)
    - National Education Association, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.60)
    - New England Regional Laboratory, 1965 (Box 17, Folder III.61)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1965 (Box 17, Folder III.62)
    - National Association of Mutual Savings Banks, 1966 (Box 17, Folder III.63)
    - Peace Corps Training Program for Tunisia -- Biographical Data, 1966 (Box 17, Folder III.64)
    - Peace Corps, 1965 (Box 17, Folder III.65)
    - Personal -- A. Lindberg, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.66)
    - Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.67)
    - J. Price, 1965-1967 (Box 17, Folder III.68)
    - Purchasing Department, 1965 (Box 17, Folder III.69)
    - Registrar's Office, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.70)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1966 (Box 17, Folder III.71)
    - Reappointments, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder III.72)
    - Salaries, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.73)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.74)
    - Conference of the Education Commission of the States, 1966 (Box 17, Folder III.75)
    - Conflict of Interest, 1965 (Box 17, Folder III.76)
    - M.S. Stevens, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder III.77)
    - Student Government Association, [undated] (Box 18, Folder III.78)
    - Student Service Wage Rates, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder III.79)
    - Tougaloo, 1966 (Box 18, Folder III.80)
    - Tougaloo, 1965 (Box 18, Folder III.81)
    - Title III Application -- Draft Tougaloo, 1966 (Box 18, Folder III.82)
    - Fund for Visiting Faculty at Tougaloo, 1966 (Box 18, Folder III.83)
    - Universities Research Association, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder III.84)
    - "U", "V" Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder III.85)
    - Wheaton-Brown Program, 1966 (Box 18, Folder III.87)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1965 (Box 18, Folder III.88)
    - Personal, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder III.89)
  - Academic Departments, Series 3. Subseries C
    - American Civilization, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder III.90)
    - Applied Math, 1960-1965 (Box 18, Folder III.91)